overclockersclub.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy - Overclockers Club

**Our Commitment To Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us, and to keep you informed of our privacy practices, we have provided this document disclosing our intent, purpose, and use of any information that is potentially private, as well as providing details on how this information is gathered.

This document was last updated May 16th 2018.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect in our forum and when you signup for a contest. Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

**Disclosure of Information**

Users of OverClockers Club are never asked to disclose information involuntarily, except whatever information is always disclosed by browsers, servers, and internet traffic as part of the normal operation of a website.  Some of that information automatically disclosed is explained under the heading "Log Files" and "Cookies".  Overclockers Club does not collect private information from its users without their knowledge.

**Registration**  
You may be required to register for a member account (free, of course) to access specific areas of our site or to get involved in our community (forums). During registration you are asked for your email.  We require all new registrations to be authenticated by you. When do this by sending you an email after you have registered to "activate" your account on Overclockers Club. This helps to cut down on spam and users that try to create more than one account on Overclockers Club. We also require that you provide your email that was assigned to you by your ISP (Internet Service Provider; AOL, Earthlink, ect.) when registering for your Overclockers Club account. However, you're email will NEVER be given or sold to advertisers, sponsors, or any other 3rd party companies. Again, we do this to cut down on users who try to signup for multiple accounts. You will not receive any further emails from Overclockers Club except in cases where you explicitly subscribe for things such as forum updates to threads, or our newsletter, or cases of exceptional need (eg for security purposes).

**Mailing List**  
The OCC (OverClockers Club) mailing list is a way for us to communicate with our dedicated readers by offering you with hot insider news and up to the minute reviews. Our mailing list readers will be the first to know when we release new reviews, how-to guides, and other big site news. All that is required by you, is a valid email address. Unlike our registration process that requires your ISP email address, our mailing list will accept any valid email address. Like our registration process, you will receive an email from us that verifies your email and your intent to join the mailing list. Overclockers Club will never sell or give your personal information to advertisers, sponsors, or any third party company.

**Log Files**

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.  Site moderators and editorial staff do not have access to this information.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. This type of cookie is used mostly in our forum. When you signin with your userid and password you can click the button that says "Remember me". The next time you visit the forum, you will automatically be logged in, thanks to cookies. By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site, but would have to enter their password and login over and over. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site, like our forum. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. Advertisers can not personally contact you in anyway whatsoever. Advertisers nor any other 3rd party has any information that can identify you personally.

**Third Party Analytics**

Overclockers Club uses Google Analytics to get an idea of how our site is used and to help improve our content.  Certain information such as your browser, and your IP address may be sent to Analytics but this information is always anonymized so that we don’t know which specific visitors are associated with what browser and we do not have access to any IP information in Analytics. Analytics may use several cookies in order to determine if you have visited the site before, but Analytics never associates any identifiable information with your visit. So we may know many people read a particular article, but we won’t know specifically who read it.  To read more about Google's use of information please see their [disclosure here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

To opt out of being counted in Google Analytics, you can install a [browser add on made by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Third Party Advertising**  
The ads appearing on Overclockers Club are delivered to users by our adserver and our advertising partners including Google Ads.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

Our privacy statement covers the use of cookies by OverclockersClub.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers, affiliates, or 3rd party sites.  You can find out more about Google's [information use here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

You can control Ad Personalisation by Google Ads and Google products by visiting the [Google Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/).

You can also learn more about other third party advertiser personalisation of ads and opt out of personalisation by [seeing this opt out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Overclockersclub.com, nor not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Surveys & Contests**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address). Contact information will NOT be sent to 3rd party's but only for us to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior choice.

**Security**  
This web site takes every reasonable precaution to protect our users' information. The Overclockers Club editorial team and staff do NOT have access to private information stored in our logs or servers. The editorial team also make their best efforts to preserve the privacy of any persons they communicate with in the course of their work on the site.

When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. On our site we have programs implemented to protect your email address in our forums. The only way that your email will be publicly avaliable is if you choose to "show" your email address in our forums so other users can contact you. On the Internet there are "Spam Bots", which surf the Internet and collect every email address they find and place them in a database, then they send junk email to all of these users. We have taken it a step higher in security and have blocked spam bots from our site.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please go to our [contact page](http://www.overclockersclub.com/pages/contact/).
